# Mario Garingo

Curriculum Vitae

55 Alex Campbell Crest.
King City Toronto Ontario, L7B0C2

⑤ (416) 200-3167

⋈ mg.mydev@gmail.com

https://mgaringodev.github.io/



## Current Employment

#### 2016 - Headache Sciences Inc., CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER

Current Develop the patent pending main algorithm of the company, to detect predisposition of migraine using machine learning and advanced signal processing techniques. Develop technical drawings and memos to communicate algorithm to a wide variety of academic and non-academic audience. Perform clinical data acquisition of patients for various pilot studies. Manage a team to identify medical regulation requirments, market research and venues of commercialization of the product. Create proposals for various grants and ethic boards which were successfully accepted.

#### 2015 - **Dementia Health**, DATA SCIENTIST

Current Develop analytical tools to identify abnormalities in the EEG of Alzheimerś subjects to autonomously differenitate them from a normalitie group. Develop novel signal processing techniques to perform feature analysis, reduction and fusion. Modify and identify approriate existing machine learning techniques to perform autonomous classification. Perform clinical data acquisition of patients for various pilot studies. Create proposals for various grants and ethic boards which were successfully accepted.

# 2012 – Cerebral Diagnostics Canada Inc., Lead Developer and Biomedical Research Current Engineer

Develop various novel analytical tools to characterize and classify a variety of neurological processes. Created novel K-complex, alpha and delta analysis for sleep medicine using EEG source localization. Lead a group of mathematicians at the Fields Institute to develop a novel brain synchonization technique to identify brain region connectivity. Established a new protocol for VEP and LEP analysis for pain using EEG and source localization. Enhancing proficiency and performance of existing proprietary programs by optimizing code and merging programs. Programing proprietary robotic arm to test and measure thresholds of pain as it relates to diabetic neuropathy and carpal tunnel syndrome. Developing a new cap system for easy recording of EEG signals. Developed brain sonifcaiton techniques. Developed pipeline, analysis and program to transform existing brain imaging techniques into holographic print ready images.

# Previous Employment

#### 2015 – 2016 University Health Network, Programmer

Developed mobile apps for android and OS, as well as various web applications. These included creating a medical adherance app in which patient adherenace were tracked and automatic reports were sent to doctors.

#### 2011 – 2012 Real Programing 4 Kids, INSTRUCTOR

Taught children ages 7-15 about the fundamentals and good programming practices of computer programming using C++, C#, Java and Visual Basics. Helped them develop computer games based on the knowledge gained in the course. Communicated effectively by using simple and clear terminology to explain complex terms.

#### 2011 – 2012 Colours Without Borders. RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Used C to acquire data from a device called the i1 pro to acquire colour information of a given colour bar. Analyzed raw spectrum of colour bar and successfully classified individual colours within a colour bar. Used C++ to create a graphical user interface(GUI) for pressman operators to maintain standard consistent colours within a printing job based on expected colour bar information and acquired colour bar information. The GUI communicated to a local and web server via SQL lite, to monitor the progression of a printing job.

#### 2010 – 2012 Ryerson Signal Analysis Research Groups, RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Used MATLAB to analyze spectrum and power densities of various EEG signals. Researched and developed algorithms to efficiently perform analysis. Used intelligent system classification techniques to group similar EEG signals. Developed a GUI in C# and MATLAB to perform different algorithms on EEG signals. Presented work and findings in weekly conference meetings.

#### Education

2013–2015 Masters of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering, Ryerson University, Toronto, Ontario

2007–2011 Bachelor in Electrical and Computer Engineering, Ryerson University, Toronto, Ontario

#### Masters Thesis

Title Audio display and environmental sound analysis of diagnostic and therapeutic respiratory sounds.

Supervisors Dr. Sridhar Krishnan

Description The objective of this work is to provide a framework to aid physicians in identifying early respiratory ailments as well as provide a means of monitoring medication compliancy for both the patient and physicians. To aid physicians identify abnormal sounds during auscultations such as crackle, this work proposes a multimedia approach in the form of audio display (AD) to enhance crackle sounds produced in respiration. This work utilize a two step AD approach in which the crackle sound is first separated from the rest of the vesicular sound and then either sonified or audified. To aid in monitoring use of medication this work proposes an environmental sound analysis (ESA) framework to autonomously quantify adherence to medication. This work employed traditional audio features to extract meaningful discriminatory information to identify the inhaler sounds from the environment with the aid of maximum relevance and minimum redundancy algorithm and the hidden markov model.

#### Certifications

2016 Independent Ethics Committe - Responsible Conduct of Research , COLLABORATIVE INSTITUTIONAL TRAINING INITIATIVE, UNIVERSITY OF MIAMI.

#### Awards

- 2016 Won Stages 1,2 and 3 of the Norman Esch Award
- 2015 Awarded 1 of 5 Ontario Brain Insitite Interns in the Province
- 2013 Awarded Best Project in the 2013 International Conference for Up-Coming Engineers

#### Technical and Personal Skills

Programming C, C++,C#, VBA, Python, Matlab, Arduino, TeX, Java Script, Java, HTML, SQL, and CSS. Languages Also basic ability with: Assembly and VHDL.

General Excellent verbal and written skills. Self-motivated and punctual. Good presentation skills. Works Business well in a team. Fast learner and quick problem solver with high attention to detail. Skills

Others Can write well organized and structured reports and memos.

## Interests and Extra-Curricular Activities

I frequently participate in machine learning algorithm competitions in oder reinforce my existing knowledge in the area of data analysis and classification while also learning new algorithms and ways to make them more efficient.

I am also an avid runner, competing in various road and trail races in the Toronto.

# Languages

English **Fluent** 

Tagalog Native Speaker Illocano Native Speaker

#### References

References available on request